# **Mohammed Saniul Haque**

Address: House-555 (4th Floor), Road-09 (Link Road),

Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka-1216

Contact: +880-1723868498 | msaniul.haque@gmail.com

LinkedIn: bd.linkedin.com/in/msaniulhaque/

## Objective

Experienced as a product cost analyst and budget controller who seeks a challenging career path where I can put my experience to use for the benefit of the organization and harness the best of my caliber. Being 3 years of internal audit experience, I utilize my audit experience to enhance organization's value.

## Experience

### Japan Tobacco International (JTI)

[April 2019 to April 2021]

### Global Supply Chain Finance Associate

- Assist in annual & strategic planning (APSP), finalize product cost standards for the factory and actual results, working closely with local and global finance teams.
- o Conduct monthly variance analysis with focus on working capital and cash flow analysis.
- Support factory controller by analyzing Non-Tobacco Materials Actual (NTM) VMCs vs BIP in terms of providing variances and presenting actual scenario to the factory management.
- o Analyze monthly purchase price variance for all consumed NTM materials.
- o Identify and propose improvements of inventory management processes.
- o Conduct financial analysis and prepare report for Management update.

### **EDISON Group (SB Tel Enterprises Limited)**

[May 2017 to April 2019]

### Senior Executive, Business Planning & Analysis

- Assist to prepare annual budget of 10 business units of Edison Group.
- o Prepare report for monthly, quarterly budget variance analysis.
- o Prepare Financials of business units on a monthly basis and consolidated for the management.
- o Prepare cost benefit analysis (CBA) of new initiative/products and service
- o Analyze post campaign financials and evaluate regular incentives and back margin calculation.
- o Conduct business model & in-depth business analysis as per management requirement.
- o Assist ad-hoc basic reporting align with business strategies.

#### ACI Limited

[February 2014 to April 2017]

- Senior Executive, Risk Management & Internal Audit (RMIA)
- Executive, Risk Management & Internal Audit (RMIA)
  - Perform following activities: Process Audit Surprise Audit, Prepayment Voucher Audit, Continuous
    Audit, Special Tasks assigned by the top management, Investigation
  - o Assist in preparing organization's risk matrix and annual audit plan
  - o Responsible for monitoring 26 depots management and planning for depot audit.
  - Prepare quarterly audit committee report



• Report audit follow-up, and to make recommendations for correcting unsatisfactory conditions, improving operations, and reducing cost.

### Education

Master of Business Administration (2012-2014)

CGPA: 3.14/4; Major: Finance & Accounting; North South University

Bachelor of Business Administration (2007-2012)

CGPA: 3.30/4; Major: Finance & Accounting; North South University

Higher Secondary Certificate (2004-2006)

GPA: 4.7/5; Concentration: Science; Rajuk Uttara Model College [Dhaka Board]

Secondary School Certificate (2002-2004)

GPA: 4.81/5; Concentration: Science; Karnaphuli Fertilizer Company School [Chittagong Board]

### **Internal Trainer**

I have been working as an internal trainers (MS Excel) in EDISON Group since May 2018.

### **Honors & Awards**

#### Maestro Excel Competition in ACI Limited-2014 [Session-2]

I was awarded as "2<sup>nd</sup> Runners-up" in Maestro Excel Competition. Total 86 employees from different departments and business units participated in the competition.

### **Employee of the Quarter in EDISON Group**

I was recognized employee of the quarter both in 3<sup>rd</sup> Quarter-2017 and 2<sup>nd</sup> Quarter-2018.

### **Knowledge & Skills**

Language: Fluent in both verbal and written aspect in English and Bengali.

**Computer**: MS Office, Photoshop, SPSS etc.

**SAP:** Having knowledge of FICO, MM and Reporting. One of the Power User of Non-Leaf SAP S/4 HANA implementation project team and actively participated in SAP UAT testing in JTI Bangladesh.

## **Personal Strengths**

- Possess good interpersonal skills, oral and writing skills;
- Organized, detail-oriented, and conscientious self-starter, able to strategies and prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks and stay calm under pressure;
- Have good analytical ability and financial data analysis;
- Have strong leadership capabilities and ability to work as a team, dedicated and self-inspiration for achieving the target.

## **Extra-Curricular Activities**

- Attended various workshop & seminars
- Performed in HSBC Young Entrepreneur Awards (YEA) Competition in 2011

## Personal Information

Name: Mohammed Saniul Haque Father's Name: Md. Jawadul Hoque Mother's Name: Rowshan Akter Date of Birth: 16 June, 1988

Nationality: Bangladeshi (By birth)

National ID: 820 036 6568

Religion: Islam

Mohammed Saniul Haque